Guide to the Anthony Taussig collection of English legal manuscripts
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Taussig Catalog # 457: 18th cent. (c. 1788) small group of papers re poaching in Norfolk [2009.7.29 S. Hughes] (Box 68)
- Taussig Catalog # 458: 18th cent. (6 Mar. 1780) case to and opinion of John Dunning [9 Aug. 2009 Ebay] (Box 68)
- Taussig Catalog # 459: 18th cent. two MS cashbooks of Robert Thorp (1782-92) [2009.8.27(a) Thomson Roddick & Medcalf] (Box 68)
- Taussig Catalog # 460: 19th cent. (1820s and 30s) documents illustrating work of Robert Thorp as clerk of peace [2009.8.27(b) Thomson Roddick & Medcalf] (Box 68)
- Taussig Catalog # 461: 18th cent. (1807) copy of case to and opinion of T. Plumer and J. Raine [2009.9.5 Fotheringham] (Box 68)
- Taussig Catalog # 462: 19th cent. MS notebook containing texts by William Blackstone and his relatives 31 + 23 pp. [2009.9.12(a) Ebay] (Box 68)
- Taussig Catalog # 463: 18th cent. (c. 1778) MS epitaph for Henry Blackstone by William Blackstone [2009.9.12(b) Ebay] (Box 68)
- Taussig Catalog # 464: 19th cent. MS catalogue of books and furniture at Narrowgate House, Alnwick with some letters from W.W. Forster Dickson [2009.10.1(a) Thomson Roddick & Medcalf] (Box 68)
- Taussig Catalog # 465: 18th cent. draft pleadings of Thomas Adams c. 1768-80 [2009.10.1(b) Thomson Roddick & Medcalf], 3 (Box 68)
- Taussig Catalog # 466: 18th cent. MS collection of documents from Alnwick archive mainly relating to dispute over control of parish [2009.10.1(c) Thomson Roddick & Medcalf], 4 (Box 68)
- Taussig Catalog # 467: 18th cent. (28 Sep. 1790) MS agreement to restrict hirings of servants from another parish [2009.10.12 Aitchison] (Box 68)
- Taussig Catalog # 468: 18th cent. MS case to A-G of Ireland and opinion of John Radcliff, 10 pp. [2009.10.23 Mayfly] (Box 68)
- Taussig Catalog # 469: 18th cent. (1789) MS case to and opinion of R.H. Williamson with two other documents [2009.10.29(a) Fotheringham] (Box 68)
- Taussig Catalog # 470: 18th cent. (1771) MS draft declaration re: libel on Protestant minister with note by John Collingwood [2009.10.29(b) Fotheringham] (Box 68)
- Taussig Catalog # 471: 18th and 19th cent. MS papers of Robert Thorp as clerk to Income Tax Commissioners 1798-1807 [2009.11.12 Thomson Roddick & Medcalf], 5 (Box 69)
- Taussig Catalog # 472: 4 Sep. 1797 ALS from Jukes Coulson to Thomas Adams re: purchase of guns, 1 p. [2009.1.19 Mullock's] (Box 69)
- Taussig Catalog # 473: 19th cent. duplicate of schedule of assessed taxes, 1825 [2009.11.30(a) Aitchison] (Box 69)
- Taussig Catalog # 474: 19th cent. (Mar. 1816) letter relating to highway dispute [2009.11.30(b) Aitchison] (Box 69)
- Taussig Catalog # 475: 16th cent. (c. 1585-95) MS manual for clerk of peace, composed in Yorkshire, 70 ff. [2009.12.20 Meyer Boswell Books] (Box 69)
- Taussig Catalog # 476: 26 Apr. 1796 MS case to and opinion of R.H. Williamson [2010.1.5 Fotheringham] (Box 69)
- Taussig Catalog # 477: 18th cent. (?1756) MS memorandum of appointment of under-clerk in Chancery [2010.1.22 Mayfly] (Box 69)
- Taussig Catalog # 478: 18th cent. (1788-89) subtantial group of letters re: dispute about rabbit warren [2010.3.2(a) Mullock's] (Box 69)
- Taussig Catalog # 479: 18th-19th cent. small group of ALS from Thomas Adams to J.J. Powell [2010.3.2(b) Mullock's] (Box 69)
- Taussig Catalog # 480: 18th cent. MS notes of King's Bench cases 1789-90, 92 pp. [2010.3.16 David Lay Auctions] (Box 69)
- Taussig Catalog # 481: 8 May 1795 ALS from J.J. Powell to Thomas Adams, 3 pp. [2010.3.20 R. Ford] (Box 69)
- Taussig Catalog # 482.1-482.3: 18th-19th cent. extensive correspondence and other papers re: Hebburne estate from Alnwick archive [2010.4.22 Thomson, Roddick & Medcalf] [1 of 2], 3 (Box 69)
- Taussig Catalog # 482.4-482.5: 18th-19th cent. extensive correspondence and other papers re: Hebburne estate from Alnwick archive [2010.4.22 Thomson, Roddick & Medcalf] [2 of 2], 2 (Box 70)
- Taussig Catalog # 483: 18th-19th cent. further correspondence and papers re: Hebburne Estate from Alnwick archive [2010.6.10(a) Thomson, Roddick & Medcalf], 6 (Box 70)
- Taussig Catalog # 484.1-484.5: 18th cent. (1774-9) extensive documentation re the will of John Cookson and related litigation [2010.6.10(b) Thomson Roddick & Medcalf] [1 of 2], 5 (Box 70)
- Taussig Catalog # 484.6-484.8: 18th cent. (1774-9) extensive documentation re the will of John Cookson and related litigation [2010.6.10(b) Thomson Roddick & Medcalf] [2 of 2], 3 (Box 71)
- Taussig Catalog # 485: 16th-18th cent. Littleton Tenures 16th cent. (printed), enlarged, interleaved and annotated with additional annotations in 18th cent., taken from writings of Sir Geoffrey Gilbert [2010.7.1 Summersgill] (Box 71)
- Taussig Catalog # 486: 18th-19th cent. MS correspondence between Thomas Adams and William Grey (attorney) with some accounts [2010.7.15(a) Thomson Roddick & Medcalf] (Box 71)
- Taussig Catalog # 487: 18th-19th cent. further MS documentation relating to Hebburne Estate from Alnwick archive [2010.7.15(b) Thomson Roddick & Medcalf], 5 (Box 71)
- Taussig Catalog # 488: 18th cent. (1791-2) three ALS from R.H. Williamson to Thomas Adams [2010.7.29(a) Fotheringham] (Box 71)
- Taussig Catalog # 489: 19th cent. (1813) MS accounts of personal estate of Thomas Adams [2010.7.29(b) Fotheringham] (Box 71)
- Taussig Catalog # 490: 19th cent. MS notebook of Robert Thorp, c. 1800, 30-40 pp. [2010.7.29(c) Fotheringham] (Box 71)
- Taussig Catalog # 491: 19th cent. (c. 1817-20) MS documents relating to estate of Alexander Adams [2010.7.31 Fotheringham] (Box 71)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 3: 2 May 1600 ALS Sir Henry Cobham to Kent justices [91.11.14(a) Phillips] (Box 72)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 9: 29 May/25 Aug 1676 two ALS Sir Richard Newdigate to Sir Walter Bagot [99.5.27 Bloomsbury Book Auctions], 2 (Box 72)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 11: 24 July 1699 LS Lord Somers to Lord Willoughby [90.10.29(b) R. Rubin] (Box 72)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 12: 6 June 1705 MS draft letter William Blathwayt to My Lord Treasurer re: American plantations [85.10.10(a) Bristow] (Box 72)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 15: 2 Oct 1722 LS Duke of Rutland to a lady [2000.6.11(c) J. Grant] (Box 72)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 16: 13 June 1723 unsigned letter from Lord Macclesfied to R. Swynfen [92.4.21(i) Quaritch] (Box 72)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 36: 30 Jan. 1786 charity brief signed by George III and Lord Sydney to Mayor of London [2004.12.3 Stride & Son] (Box 72)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 46: c. 1800 ALS A. Highmore to Mr Wilks [97.2.13 Questor Rare Books] (Box 72)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 51: 13 Feb 1806 ALS Sir Frederick Eden to William Cobbett [94.12.5(a) J. Wilson] (Box 72)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 65: 13 July 1818 ALS Sir George Onesiphoros Paul to Cap. Charleton [99.6.3(b) A.R. Heath] (Box 72)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 73: 11 Mar. 1822 ALS Rev. R. Butcher to Sir Richard Birnie [provenance not traced] (Box 72)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 79: 1829-30 letter book of Lieut. R. Williamson commander of Revenue cutter Sylvia mainly to Capt. Jackson re: smuggling in Weymouth area, 38 pp. [2001.2.22 J. Browning] (Box 72)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 91.1-Misc. 91.2: 1837-60 letter books containing large number of copy letters received at Lyme Regis Coastguard station, including detailed information on movements of smugglers and their ships (in some cases with drawings showing method of concealment), 2 vols., 386 + 326 pp. [2000.11.16 G. and D.I. Marrin & Sons], 2 (Box 73)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 94: 6 Nov. 1839 ALS John Childs to John Rylance re: jury trial [2002.1.31 J. Browning] (Box 73)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 99: 8 Aug. 1847 ALS Sir (Jonathan) Frederick Pollock to [Frank?] Haywood, from Lancaster, accepting an invitation on behalf of himself and 'my brother Wightman'. [1989.21.21 Winifred Myers] (Box 73)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 109: 8 Sep. 1868 ALS Lord Chelmsford to Sir Richard Baggallay [89.12.21(d) W. Myers] (Box 73)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 116: 1897-98 group of six copy letters from British Legation, Tangier, Morocco re: administration of justice in Tangier and Gibraltar, one letter to Lord Salisbury and five letters to Chief Justice of Gibraltar [2001.5.16 Dominic Winter Book Auctions] (Box 73)
- Taussig Catalog # Misc. 119: 9 May 1914 ALS Sir John Simon to Miss Mackenzie re: House of Lords list [89.12.21(d) W.Myers] (Box 73)